<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenSCAD on J. Felipe Gonzalez, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/openscad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OpenSCAD on J. Felipe Gonzalez, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 09:04:40 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/openscad/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Facilitating Programming-based 3D Computer-Aided Design using Bidirectional Programming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/facilitating-programming-based-cad-with-bidirectionnal-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/facilitating-programming-based-cad-with-bidirectionnal-programming/</guid>
      <description>Hey ! This project is aimed at improving the 3D design experience for users working with programming-based CAD applications where you must design in a text editor with a programming language while the application renders the visual representation of the model in a viewport after compiling, like OpenSCAD and JSCAD. It draws on insights from my PhD research, which you can explore in more detail here.&#xA;While many CAD tools feature intuitive drag-and-drop interfaces, programming-based CAD offers a unique, code-driven approach that unlocks powerful design possibilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Bidirectional Programming in Constructive Solid Geometry-Based CAD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/introducing-bidirectionnal-programmin-in-csg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/introducing-bidirectionnal-programmin-in-csg/</guid>
      <description>Programming-based CAD applications are powerful, but they come with challenges. Unlike traditional drag-and-drop interfaces, scripting in tools like OpenSCAD can be frustrating, especially when trying to locate specific parts of the model in the code or move an element in 3D space.&#xA;In this project, I introduced bidirectional programming for Constructive Solid Geometry (CSG) CAD tools. This approach lets you seamlessly switch between coding and the 3D view, allowing for easy navigation and editing.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
