<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Haptics on J. Felipe Gonzalez, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/haptics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Haptics on J. Felipe Gonzalez, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 09:08:10 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/haptics/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adaptic: A Shape Changing Prop with Haptic Retargeting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/adaptic-a-shape-changing-prop-with-haptic-retargeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/adaptic-a-shape-changing-prop-with-haptic-retargeting/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We present Adaptic, a novel &amp;ldquo;hybrid&amp;rdquo; active/passive haptic device that can change shape to act as a proxy for a range of virtual objects in VR. We use Adaptic with haptic retargeting to redirect the user’s hand to provide haptic feedback for several virtual objects in arm’s reach using only a single prop. To evaluate the effectiveness of Adaptic with haptic retargeting, we conducted a within-subjects experiment employing a docking task to compare Adaptic to non-matching proxy objects (i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptic: A Shape Changing Prop with Haptic Retargeting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/adaptic-shape-changing-prop-and-vr-haptic-reatergeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/adaptic-shape-changing-prop-and-vr-haptic-reatergeting/</guid>
      <description>Imagine interacting with virtual objects in VR and feeling as if you&amp;rsquo;re actually handling them, all while using just a single device. That’s exactly what we aimed to achieve with Adaptic, our innovative haptic device. Unlike traditional props, Adaptic is a shape-changing device that can transform its form to match various virtual objects you’re manipulating in VR.&#xA;Here’s how it works: Adaptic uses a clever technique called haptic retargeting to adjust its shape and provide realistic feedback for different virtual items.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
